Young Professional with studies in Computer Science and Mathematics accomplished in software development, testing, and documentation. Published researcher with experience in data analytics, digital image processing, and computer vision. Experienced conference organizer and program administrator. Skilled tutor and teacher with a passion for continued learning.

CORE PROFICIENCIES

Languages & Computing	Applied Experience	Notable Coursework
➤ Java & OOP Design	➤ Image Processing & Computer Vision	➤ Statistics for Data Analysis
➤ Python	➤ High-Throughput Plant Phenotyping	➤ Regression Analysis
➤ C++, C# & ASP.Net Development	➤ Parallel & Batch processing	➤ Calculus I, II, III, Advanced
➤ SQL for Database Management	➤ Software Development & Testing	➤ Data Structures & Algorithms
➤ R Programming for Data Analysis	➤ Data Science & Machine Learning Tools	➤ ASP.Net Development
➤ Bash – Unix Shell	➤ HTCondor Computing Cluster	➤ Modelling & Experimental Design

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Illinois State University, Normal, IL Data Science, P.E.E.R Program

October 2018-Present

- Performed ordinal data analysis for faculty within the Family Consumer Sciences Department.
- Evaluated study strength and recommended data acquisition improvements.

Illinois State University, Normal, IL

August 2018-Present

Teaching Assistant, Department of Mathematics

- Instructed MAT 150: Fundamentals of Statistical Reasoning: creating and proctoring exams and grading.
- Tutored students, addressing questions and concerns.
- Presented class progress reports to my supervisor, recommending course scheduling changes.

11th International Symposium for Biomathematics, Ecology, Education and Research Conference Organizer

- Organized all speaker sessions and mini-symposiums schedule, coordinated with speakers, including plenary and keynote speakers, approving all materials and abstracts to ensure quality content.
- Utilized Microsoft Suite tools for conference administration, i.e. conference website, program, attendee materials.
- Coordinated pre-conference and on-site support at hosting institution, Arizona State University.

Donald Danforth Plant Science Center, St. Louis, MO **Bioinformatics Intern**

May 2018- August 2018

- Contributed development of PlantCV, a suite of Computer Vision tools for High-throughput Phenotyping.
- Implemented a new color space standardization method in PlantCV as a subpackage and developed a new, robust method for background subtraction, including associated software testing and documentation.
- Processed over 200,000 images of *Sorghum bicolor* on Danforth's HTCondor computing cluster, applying parallel computing techniques and batch processing.
- Analyzed preliminary phenotype data from image processing and prepared for downstream processing.
- Supported laund of PlantCV version 3 release at "PlantCV Day," and worked with clients to collect requests for future tools and development
- Published contributing author for PlantCV citation.

Scribe America, St. Louis, MO

April 2017-April 2018

Medical Scribe, SSM St. Mary's Hospital

- Documented patient charts by assisting ER physicians during patient appointments using Epic Healthcare Clinical Software to maintain accurate patient records, administering provider messaging and support.
- Completed training and on-going education for required medical terminology and ER practice protocols.
- Assisted patients by coordinating comforts, i.e. food, pillows, blankets.

EDUCATION

Post-Baccalaureate Studies in Computer Science & Bioinformatics Fontbonne University, St. Louis, MO

- GPA: 3.816/4.0
- Dean's List, all semesters

Bachelor of Science in Mathematics

Illinois State University, Normal, IL

- GPA 3.25/4.0
- Honors Program
- Accelerated admission entering with sophomore standing

RESEARCH

Donald Danforth Plant Science Center

Image Processing for high-throughput Phenotyping

Summer 2018

Citation: Berry JC, Fahlgren N. Pokorny A.A., Bart RS, Veley, KM (2018) An automated high-throughput method standardizing image color profiles to improve image-based plant phenotyping. *PeerJ* 6:e5727. https://doi.org/10.7717/peerj.5727

- Implemented a method for color space standardization as a new subpackage in PlantCV, a software for Plant Phenotyping written in Python using OpenCV, Numpy, Matplotlib and others, available on GitHub.
- Developed, tested and completed documentation for the subpackage, available here: https://plantcv.readthedocs.io/en/latest/
- Presented research as the only M.S. student speaker within the program curriculum at the 11th International Symposium for Biomathematics, Ecology, Education and Research (BEER-IX), Tempe AZ, October 2018.

Department of Mathematics, Illinois State University

Undergraduate Research in Mathematics

Spring 2016

Citation: Abels B, Brown N, Jordan H, Pokorny AA. (N.d.) ±Skolem-Type Difference Sets.

- Developed methods for partitioning 3-tuple ±Skolem-Type and ±Langford-Type Difference Sets.
- Generalized methods for partitioning to m-tuple sets.
- Applied to decomposition of circulant digraphs into cycles.
- Presented research at the Undergraduate Research Symposium, Illinois State University, April 2016.

VOLUNTEER & EXTRACURRICULAR ACTIVITIES

•	Student Member, Association for Computing Machinery	2017 - <i>Current</i>
•	Circus Performer, Bumbershoot Aerial Arts & Gamma Phi Circus	2010 - Current
•	Women in Technology and Science	2018 - Current
•	Software Development Contributor, PlantCV	2018
•	Private Calculus Tutor for a Ladue High School Student	2017 - 2018
•	Calculus Tutor, Honors Program, Illinois State University	Spring 2015
•	Aerial Silks Coach, Jr. Gamma Phi Circus, Thomas Metcalf School	2013-2014